Aloha everybody welcome to the liftoff
of the radical catalyst rad cat I'm
coming to you from farm in Hawaii and
I'm a musician I deal in musical
wellness I deal in a bit of a Johnny
Appleseed character I deal and a lot of
immediacy mixed with familiarity and
what we're all aspiring to to do in this
club so that said I'm happy you're all
here and I'll start out with this week
of the of the Red Cat Club the radical
catalyst Club and so this is and this is
the the opening night everybody might be
in a different time zone here from
Venice Beach five five pm rude you're in
Hawaii everybody different place but I
hope we're feeling comfortable so I
would like to take over the screen to
share a little bit of the slice of how
this initiative started Aloha everybody
welcome to the liftoff of the radical
catalyst rad cat I'm coming to you from
a farm in Hawaii and I'm a musician I
deal in musical wellness I deal in a bit
of a Johnny Appleseed character I deal
and a lot of immediacy
mixed with familiarity and what we're
all aspiring to do in this club so that
said I'm happy you're all here and I'll
start out with this little anthem week
of the of the Red Cat Club the radical
catalyst Club and so this is and this is
the the opening night everybody might be
in a different time zone here from
Venice Beach I am here five five pm rude
you're in Hawaii everybody's in a little
bit of a different place but I hope
we're feeling comfortable so I would
like to take over the screen to share a
little bit of the slides of how this
initiative started after a rude new and
I met with a we had the invitation from
Burning Man to come together and gather
and convene at Esalen to see how we
could broaden the power and use the
philosophy and principles of Burning Man
beyond the event to have a positive
impact in the world and after the event
we wanted to keep momentum and and
figure out how we could use the
knowledge and the network of Burning Man
to have a positive impact and then
catalyzed by what is happening right now
in our world we said you know more than
ever we have trapped ourselves in a
system that is about to destroy us and
and how can we get out of it and and
that's a question where we've been
brainstorming thinking about like how
can we do this and obviously that's
something you know we need to do
together and and and we use this kind of
playful gamification of Mario as a
background because you know we need to
we need to have that positive light and
positive feel in the development of
solutions and in the gatherings we have
it needs to be positive needs to be a
positive change but it's a very very
serious time where we need to radically
redirect the course of humanity and and
that is the the idea behind the radical
catalyst Club is to bring people
together in in this case virtually to
come up with ideas of what is that
direction and what are the tools and
what do we need what and there's a lot
of people and and and Jordan Hall will
talk about that like there's a lot of
smart people there's a lot of smart
initiatives happening but we need to
bring that together and and figure out
what focus we want and this is the time
where we are forced to slow down and do
that and so we defined the mission where
we said we want to co-create places
where people can be to change they wish
to see it in the world and of course a
play on Gandhi but co-creation is a
really really important aspect and and I
will keep some pace because we need time
for to listen to Jordan and then to have
time to interactively talk about that
topic and how we can make a change and
plant seeds as I said this is the
opening week of the radical catalyst
Club and it's a look at it like a little
bit like a nightclub or a cabaret club
or a club where we have different
programming's going on and tonight is a
moment where we have a speaker a guest
speaker and talk around that tomorrow is
a different type of a of an oven club
night so to say where we are more in a
work session and share our projects and
talk around those projects with each
other and share what we need very
practical what do we each need what do
we have to
give and what are we committed to do
within this this club community and
obviously this rat cat club as a playful
word of radical catalyst club we need
everybody we need all the smart cats all
the thinkers scientists artists to come
together and that's the principle today
we have Jordan Hall turning crisis into
an opportunity and at the end of this
session we'll talk a little bit more
about tomorrow Julian I've submitted
Esalen and it was a conference on how
can we apply the massive amount of joy
and bliss and self-organizing change it
happens at Burning Man and how can we
apply that to the rest of the world or
enable the rest of the world to actually
live into that as much as they were
willing to to observe that and so my
work has largely been full-time on
working on building those systems and
that's how I met Bonnie and Bonnie's
work has been about creating these
self-organizing self open participatory
ization systems as she calls it and and
it's through Buckley that she introduced
Jordan Hall as a as an opportunity
presenter for tonight so I'm gonna
introduce Bonnie to introduce Jordan and
that'll be the last intro to an intro to
an intro yeah so introducing Jordan is a
is a big job because there's too much to
say so I you know people who know Jordan
he's a brilliant systems thinker but he
has this really unique coat approach
called deep cold which gets at the key
underlying dynamics of what's going on
what I think is especially appreciate it
is that he doesn't do this for the
simple play of ideas but in order to
make sense of the world so we can make
better choices and I think that
resonates with everybody here so just
kind of a set up and
Jordan's really good speaking but just
to set this up I was wanted to ask
Jordan to weave together three notions
so the notions systemic fragility you
know at the system's level at an
individual sovereignty so you know how
does the individual sovereignty play
into systemic fragility and then
collective sense making can try to
interweave those around and and maybe
using the recent coronavirus situation
that we're all dealing with yeah so how
does the corona virus play out with
systemic fragility individual
sovereignty and collective sense-making
I just want to explain to people what
we're talking about by assistant
facility by the way it's just the idea
is that when one thing drags everything
else breaks with it with it and how do
we create a decentralized system by
which that prevents that which is the
culture that the Bernie man called cures
or actually kind of you know
unconsciously creating is this how the
quickest stuff organized culture that
that is that's independent of that
fragile system right so you see all
right right now it's the shift to the
notion of opportunity and then we'll and
then connect that to the notion of
individual sovereignty it can be very
to get out of a system thank systems
dynamics have a characteristic in
complexity science is called an
attractor sort of like being in a really
steep bowl and if you're if you're an
ant trying to push a grape up the edge
of a bowl that's a lot of push
indecision let go it rolls down to the
bottom a Sisyphean task of getting out
of the system but what happens is is
that as the system fragility increases
there are moments like the moment that
we're in where you actually get the bowl
gets less that's deep it gets shallower
I mean the amount of energy necessary to
move you out of that basis of attraction
goes down and if you get a cascade
effect by the way if you actually get
you know many many systems have become
fragile next to each other in the whole
system is fragile then you get this
situation where small amounts of
spillover hit subsystems those break
they send spillover you get a
catastrophic cascade effect across the
entire thing and using the bowl metaphor
that's like the bowl going perfectly
flat meaning that now the ball could
roll anywhere there's absolutely no
constraint so it can do otherwise
something like chaos various small
amounts of energy can lead to very big
changes now for folks like yourselves if
you're actually thinking about change
this means that you've got a way of
looking at strategic operations if
you're trying to push the ball up the
edge of the of the bowl when the bowl is
deep that's a lot of energy like it's
like trying to change the American
school system in 1985 good luck that's a
lot of energy lots of things are linked
together and pulling it into a certain
location you can work a lifetime and
only move it a little tiny bit but if
you hit at a moment when a moment that
what the Greeks called Kairos a moment
where possibility has emerged and
actuality is wide open but the book with
the field is flat well some sense you
can't help but change things there's no
way to avoid it and now change becomes
not just but becomes very very easy and
the question then becomes can you
actually store the change in a preferred
direction and that becomes the thinking
new things are always intrinsically
groups like we are only conscious we
were operating around the campfire use
around the campfire like this particular
gathering we actually able to enter into
a space of consciousness which is the
space where we collaborate design
the kinds of things that we actually
wanted them do together and we design
our culture around the campfire in the
space of shared consciousness so what
happens is is that if we're able to
remove ourselves from the addictions and
distractions of the chaos of the
breakdown of the formal systems and
settle into our individual sovereignty
to recognize the end of the day that we
actually can and must always be
responsible for our own choices we're
gonna get to sense-making in a second
then we can reconnect relearn the skills
and skillfulness of supporting each
other and collective intelligence and
from that position begin the process of
redesigning and co-creating the place
that we'd like to go in some sense it's
pretty simple it's just practically
difficult is this the way that ice
crystals form on a very still pond if
you take a look at it very if you sort
of do a stop-motion film of it you'll
see that they form in in clusters one
little tiny location where the the water
has transformed from liquid to crystal
and what a crystal does the way a
crystal grows is it actually changes the
probability of the water around it
turning into ice that's how a crystal
grows so what happens is is that one
person who has become capable of
engaging in their own sovereignty with
themselves and engaging in collaborative
sense making becomes a crystal and when
two people connect that crystal becomes
stronger and it has more capacity to
create influence to shift the
possibility space of the area around it
and there's many many of these going on
like I've never met well almost anybody
here I think I've met Bonnie and Cori I
don't think anybody here I've actually
met before so you guys are doing this
right you're in your own little crystal
and Bonnie ends up actually being one of
these things that connects crystals and
I got a bunch of crystals I'm touching
and as the crystals grow together those
connections become very strong as long
as the binding becomes effective it
creates all kinds of interesting
creativity in humans because your tribe
is doing stuff that my tribes aren't
doing and that's perfect what we want my
tribe might be working on problem
domains that your tribe thinks for
stupid
because eventually if we figured
something out then that's something that
may be valuable do you see this a
burning man all the time oh my gosh
I remember going and seeing the list of
things that people are doing and it
ranged from the was it the absurd the
amazing the horrifying and the ludicrous
simultaneously and that's great that
that's that fuckin didn't see that comes
up when people begin to actually turn
themselves towards the things they're
naturally attracted to and then you've
got a well-functioning heterogeneous
rich sort of lomi context which is the
natural characteristic of humans and
which by the way is intrinsically
resilient and then that that construct
me think about would happen if you took
the Burning Man camp and somebody would
just like to put a big-ass wall right
through the middle of it so you just
couldn't get across neither side would
die and it's like a stash it's like a
space what's called a starfish Burning
Man is like a starfish not like a spider
take a spider and you cut it in half you
got a dead spider take a starship and
cut it in half you actually get to
starfish out of it Burning Man is the
same kind of thing right that the
richness of that of that heterogeneous
is it what's the right term for this
harmony its head of lodging is harmony
there's difference but the difference
has a way of being in right relationship
with difference on the other side and
those two words together homeless it's
and it's not like how do we do this
there's a very important thing that's
coming up to me so that can figure out
how to grab a hold of it by the way
we're not just gauging in collaborative
that's making far better than talking
about it right it's just to be doing it
and see what it feels like because for
everybody as far as I can tell everybody
here I've ever met
the way they actually go about sense
making I can infinitely nuance then like
the where do you actually look and talk
and feel when you're actually just doing
your thing the more I know you're
actually doing your thing can you share
with people what sense making is
something everyone knows well since
making
well I'm gonna do my weird thing which
is to say this is gonna sound a little
bit nerdy but it'll be okay the way I've
been thinking about it is something like
there's perception first-order
perception and as what do you want to
call you professor bonita sister bonita
what's the right frame here as has
taught me the old lady with the dog the
old lady with it with the dog now
they'll be with the horses that's what i
recognized yet we have a wide variety of
sensory apparatus right it's not
whatever wherever these five senses
there's you know bajillions of them so
it's perception of course all these
diverse senses so for the first step of
sense making is a tournament and it's
tuning in your capacity to actually
listen to the variety and the panoply of
senses that you have so that as much of
reality is interacting with you as much
as possible for Vicki calls this like
conforming to reality you know becoming
becoming water becoming liquid and fluid
so that the actual shape of the reality
that you're in is the shape that you're
perceiving like really flowing over it
and having almost a tactile sensing of
the actual shape of the environment that
you're operating become as fluid as you
can get don't try to like only grab it a
little bit that's one then
this notion of integration this notion
of wholeness you know how do you
actually take that that in infinitesimal
diversity and by the way varying levels
of subtlety of perception and bring it
into a felt sense of wholeness something
that you can actually do something with
that sense making sense making is
actually coming into a dispositional
relationship with the whole of reality
as far as you can perceive it and
nonetheless have a capacity to be
oriented in the direction of making
effective choices it's a skill right
it's the capacity that is developed by
the way can you all hear my phone
trippin at me I apologize if it's
annoying people try to hit me all the
time I can't get it we could be quiet is
like so you like get as close to what is
real as possible right so be as real as
possible and then I realized that
sometimes we make the mistakes sometimes
change makers make the mistake that
they're trying to change reality
actually we're trying to change the
bullshit and the illusion and the
delusions and these formal systems that
we put on top of reality and so that I
just thought of that
so that just that just that's really I
think something there's something there
you know yeah that's beautiful because
if you think about it then you say okay
if I'm a change maker and I'm trying to
change reality and I'm an awful lot like
that and trying to push the ball up the
edge of the bowl except the bowl is now
the Grand Canyon and the ball is you
know a thousand pound wrecking ball
which is to say it ain't gonna happen
reality is not going to change but the
bullshit if you kid if you change the
bullshit which they just become in
relationship with what really is the
case that then makes it a flat plane and
then your choices become effective
choices now you cannot help but change
the the experience that you're in
because you're simply seeing what
reality is making available what's
unfolding in front of you what is the
moment of Kairos where the possibility
of choice is that
maximum fluidity so that is this whoa
Wayne Ocean it's really a thing there's
ways to watch what's happening and
notice that you can step back and not
push so hard and see where the
possibility isn't just nudge a little
bit and then step back and nudge a
little bit
so Jordan where do you see these flows
of change where people are in that
liquid state of like you know observing
the reality in that felt sense and
they're doing are collectively creating
their own sovereignty to make change and
systemic change in this moment of like
kind of a you know what the systems are
becoming a flattened a little bit and
change is this is a good time to
actually come up with new models for a
change but where do you see this or what
do you see openings well as you're
saying that the first thing that comes
in my mind is a very wise individual
named uh Stefan Martin oh I worked with
him quite a bit about a year ago said to
me no movements no more movements and
that comes to mind first and the thing
the reason why I think what I think is
meant by that is this notion that what a
movement does is it gets rid of the
heterogeneity in the wholeness it
creates a new layer of bullshit that
gets everybody to lose their local
perception and subordinate their choice
making to some much narrower frame of
what reality is because the answer
because as I was imagining that as
you're asking the question is trying to
just sort of okay what was my perception
my perceptions is that that now when the
system enters into these states of
fragility the answer is the gaps are
everywhere all over the place
ants there's nothing nothing like one or
two gaps although by hypothesis there
are a number of very they're very
leverageable places but the best thing
is to look close at hand look at the
place where you can make the most
effective choices very narrow to where
you are oftentimes it's going to be
things like relationships that are very
close and then a little bit in the place
that you're at and the whole point
though is that if the consciousness of a
larger group of people all more or less
are due
that kind of thing and if we're all the
back back to Bernie man if I take like a
stop-motion photography and I watch
Burning Man well I don't see like one
guy saying okay everybody build that now
and do this what I see is this like this
it almost looks like a natural system
like the way that snow falls on the
ground are just kind of emerges it's
because every individual person in
relationship with their local context is
beginning to sense what is the way that
they can best at give give to what has
happened and collaboratively in the
context of the whole in some cases it's
like okay I'm gonna grab that piece of
PVC pipe and carry it over here in some
cases it means I'm gonna grab this bike
and move it over there alright and
there's that that notion of flowing and
recognizing that we're actually trying
and have to contemplate of holes as
holes that's the key now the keys we
have to actually really be mindful but
we're always in relationship as a whole
and contemplate the whole as a whole and
so in some sense we all have to kind of
pick it up which is more or less us
we're it to pick us up and each one of
us kind of nudging pieces I've been
carrying it ever so carefully we can
kind of hold it and move it to a
different location
I mean Burnett works best when you're
not like it you don't have a schedule of
events but you walk through and this not
just that thing and it's this group and
that group then it's another group it
decides to do something else and it just
constantly emerges naturally and that's
why they don't like being called a
festival because the festival has a
schedule of the events and festival as
the guys in charge of it it tells you
what's up yeah so so if I go back to the
notion of the question of those people
for whom being a burner as part of their
lived experience and by the way for
everyone who isn't that you Quakers are
equally capable in this kind of thing
and I think are rare burners but maybe
not exclusively impossible it's that
body embodied capacity it's just knowing
how to act in that way and then choosing
to act in that way and everybody else
beginning to notice shits going crazy
everywhere but those guys seemed not to
be freaking out what's that all about
and again you don't teach you do and
just buying the act of doing you begin
to do the thing and everybody else
begins to learn because everybody Minh
beings learned through emulation and wit
they cannot possibly learn through
didactics and by the way we should be
able to kill human beings learn to
emulation via people who may perceive to
be like them in a
meaningful way now what that means of
course is very respectable and in many
ways I have very little in common with
many of the people in this room and it's
the same time we may actually be right
next to each other in terms of lightness
so it's not there's no way of knowing
but it's when you sense something you're
whoa there's something there that I
actually really feel is a way for me to
learn that channel of learning through
emulation is vast so be we should be
aware of that right very careful
teaching that we spend so much time in
school there's a very bad model of what
that function is we have this notion
it's if we're crazy right it goes in
both directions on the one hand you
never emulate because there's no one to
emulate there's a teacher who's clearly
not you and all the other kids anything
you do like them is wrong so emulation
is extinguished in our capacities and
then this is sort of crazy didactic we
construct which is where all of
attention is gone so if they're
unlearned all that shit very quickly
like as rapidly as humanly possible and
this is a good opportunity right we have
this cool opportunity where none of the
kids are at school and all the people
are kind of pulled from their addictions
by you if you're not at the job that's
taking your time for a long time that's
scary I get it it's very scary but
trauma has the opportunity of pushing
you into a place where you can in fact
in desire to move to a different
location but either I was talking to
Zack about this your hashtag don't go
back to normal you know people who
undergo trauma if they actually are
brought back to normal it's very
disorienting it feels uncanny because
their body and soul knows that they have
changed almost not normal it's now an
artificial T it's normality this is
gonna happen after World War one in
Western civilization and shit broke in
World War one the world was broken but
instead of being able to actually move
into a new location some people tried
and they actually ended up doing both
super creative and also crazy stuff they
tried to move into a new location but
the culture in general try to return to
normality normalcy I think was the term
and so should had to break even worse
just a little bit down the road grab on
no no I think that's that's a big
leverage point here you know we were
talking about how you know it seems
silly but because many of you probably
have you know haven't gone to work every
day in this kind of a bullshit job but
fifteen days not doing that the organism
is going to gonna see oh why am I really
gonna do that again
you know kids 15 to two months then they
go into summer break four or five months
out of school and they noticed like did
I really am I really dumber now you know
maybe not you don't see you I think that
it's important to understand that this
is processing and many many people and
without being able to you won't see it
reported you won't see it on the
internet you might see a couple of blogs
people sharing this but but trying to
notice this in your own community like
[Music]
an understanding these dynamics you're
talking about that it's like it's a big
it's a big deal for parents to be locked
down with their kids and noticing and
their parents quite often yeah it's like
an intergenerational family for the
first time and but not just like at
Thanksgiving will you go through these
rituals and you all pretend but like
after 1520 days there's some reality
that's it is hard to bullshit for twenty
days in a row yeah so for me there's an
awful lot of leverage and opportunity
but you have to be able to see it
because it's not going to be you know
broadcast as a collective thing right
yeah it I get this vision of there being
some way for people to just sort of
support each other you know I actually
had a what was that who was it I said
conversation the friend of mine in in
Utah and he was in a particular location
in in kind of this developmental lark
let's say and the denial had not yet
broken said I see where you are and if
things change just reach out or here in
Texas I'm back in the place that I grew
up and my dad was talking to a friend of
his and what was it so I pulled the
trigger pretty quickly I put my family
in the RV I don't know what almost a
month ago they were driving out to Texas
my wife's like what are you talking
about I said well we like campus let's
just imagine we're going on a camping
trip and if it turns out whatever come
back that'll be an interesting story but
I land in my parents house and my dad
starts talking to his friends and of
course particularly in the Texas Hill
Country was very much not considered to
be a real thing right and then suddenly
we're in quarantine and his buddies are
sent himself is about what a pussy is
but he's like you know after a little
bit of time they they flip they're like
wait a minute hold on what's this all
about if you sort of you stay open okay
I hear where you are and that's great
and by the way maybe we're wrong but if
if over time there's a shift in their
unconsciousness and you're there then
there's suddenly is a hole on with
what's going on here I'm not looking for
a little bit more and you're you're now
more established you've kind of been
doing this for a while she can now
support and that that's support network
of actually just people who know each
other like building the relation ality
from the inside out and then what you
hope to have happen is that that you're
basically your tribe intersects with
another tribe now your camp your burn a
man camp has a relationship and
intersects with another camp and there's
a relationality at that level unique in
German there's something that happens at
a bigger context when tribes are now
coordinating with other tribes and
barely getting to build interior tea and
exterior tea across the boundary of
collaboration
like how what kind of contract can you
imagine online that that enabling that
to happen in the neighborhood or in a
you know community
how would you sort of like try to help
enable that to happen like in this given
flattened amount of period right now I
mean the physical embodied community
yeah yeah and that's a good question
fortunately I'm a such a high peg
introvert that in terms of interacting
with other people I I'm not very skilled
at it I've got a lot of friends and my
friends were almost all virtual I know a
few people who live near me not a lot
like saying malware force of your
virtual so like how would you you know
prepared the how would you get people to
collaborate virtually now so that when
we are allowed to get out of the house
we actually got to know what to do
campfires lots and lots and lots of
campfires stop wasting your time
engaging in broadcast media and stop
wasting your time skimming the the sort
of scummy surface of social media start
doing a lot more of these kinds of
things an interlocking network of
campfires who inside the the Dunbar to
limit is Magic you should be having four
or five conversations you have a
conversation like this every single day
I imagine how much consciousness is
being woven together like not exactly
the same a group of people the screw
people will has to have continuity you
have to build coherency inside this
group but then you know each and every
person here needs to be having two or
three or four other conversations that's
a mesh that mesh can get work done and
then you talk about virtual campfires
for now they're all virtual for now yeah
and embodied campfires are great if you
have the possibility to embody campfires
hallelujah in many cases this kind of
trying to read figure out how to do the
whole extended multi-generational family
which is a lot of work and frankly it's
good it's important work right that's
what most meaningfulness of course is in
relation ality with your family I think
those are the only people who ever who
knew you when you were little and the
people who ultimate at the end of the
day when you die it's where things are
gonna gonna drop are these weird people
who suddenly you kind of abandon to move
to the big city and that's been a huge
cultural wreck so being forced to
relearn how to actually be in family
with each other is kind of a really
serious blessing and that's kind of the
first step of being able to actually do
community is to have that skill
because how do we do this to be in
community is to be able to deal with the
reality that other people are hard to
deal with mm-hmm
all right the contemporary environment
ever since what probably the forties
increasingly over time we've had the
opportunity to migrate elsewhere fuck
the people who have heard of to deal
with I'm gonna move to the big city and
be around people who were a lot like me
well even better in the virtual
environment fuck the people who are
right next to me imma go to the virtual
environment people find people who
either Cenac see like me or I'll block
everybody else and have them still to
bubble three people who are all kind of
circling we have to relearn that so if
you can relearn that binding that
binding is powerful stuff because then
you can actually do stuff across
boundaries interesting about sense
making is that you know you have you're
stuck with your family and then you have
to learn the difficulties of that but
then when you co-creating or meaningful
it's gonna be turn into a family you're
gonna have difficult quote difficult
people are different from you that
you're gonna have a hard time with but
if you don't get through that projects
not going to happen
exactly exactly is that it helps you
understand why we're actually you know
disconnected and disharmonious and where
that's coming from
well what I like about this and and what
Jordans message is I was going to put
this in your introduction but I was
feeling prefer time is this notion of
being able to see from the system's
level is very high systems level because
our world are so complex and being able
to deconstruct that but understanding it
has to be tied into this human level of
family and perception and I think that
this is for me where the emergent
adjacent possible is and I you know we
have Monica here on this call so kind of
talking to her reality to and that is
there's this knowing that somehow this
very new way this you know Burning Man
new emergence is somehow dependent on
reclaiming this old structure of
intergenerational transmission and I
think so there's some people that are
really into this new emergent but they
have not yet been able to repair their
relationships with their family and so
that that stunted miss is going to carry
over into their system level work and
it's this this two sides of the
clamshell the gap that that has not what
waster okay Easter there's a pearl in
there the to talk about because there's
a there's a pearl in there you know
pearls are born of irritation just
reflecting on the reality that if you're
if you're if you're interaction with
somebody if you're interpreting it
introduce real co-creative collaborative
space and they haven't dealt with the
shit of their own personal projections
around their mom their dad and their
older sister they're gonna bring that
right into the middle of the
collaboration exactly when it gets hot
and that isn't here's to deal with it
it's really hard to deal with that in
the middle of an actual creative
collaboration right so the second table
stakes simple stocks like get rid of
that stuff so you've actually this when
I type a solution of sovereignty is
those kinds of things and then then the
space of creative collaboration becomes
a lot more fluid because you can let's
talk about multi perspectives /
multi-perspective perspectival this
notion of strong heterogeneity in the
context of wholeness we want to have
that right you want to interact with
somebody whose epistemology there's life
experiences whose modality of sensing is
very distant from your own well what
that means is that it's
to communicate for a while it's gonna
sound very weird you know it's what's
that phrase you've just been eating like
the eyes in the ear is communicating to
each other how they even begin to try
but if you can hold it together and you
can actually have enough maturity and
enough ability to listen to the
connection the power and that gradient
is enormous so that's kind of that's the
that's the work right building that
capacity who enable extremely high
differential in a well held whole and
not smoosh it together right not the
artificiality of the what does it call
the the diversity and inclusion ideology
which is just a smooshing it together
and pretending that it's real but
actually really figuring out to
recognize that there's a singularity in
relationship with singularity and
there's a real reality of trying to
actually get that relationality be rich
hey we have a question so anyway does
anyone have a question that's what I'm
going to open up to go to gallery view
does anyone have a question you had a
question I want me to read it out loud
or so just answer it cuz everybody's
reading it go ahead ask my question
Jordan is thank you for for for these
insights like how to get out of the
system and how to look at this this time
to get out of it can you share a little
bit about what you on a personal level
do to to make a change and how you work
together with others what are the things
you're doing what are the projects what
are the type you focus your attention on
that you've chosen to do and how do you
choose to collaborate with others are
you referring to right now like in the
past three weeks or more broadly now
what what do you choose to do like
you're talking about speaking but to
actually make crystals together and to
stick those crystals together to kind of
become one and one is 11 instead of one
and one is two so my question is
do you choose to do can you share
something of the of the type of projects
and specifically in this time that you
choose to focus your attention to and
that you try to connect with with others
sure what I would say this is almost the
experience that I'm kind of feeling now
so let's just focus on now
maybe because now is the kind of an
interesting and powerful environment
Kairos right this this kind of time
where things happen very rapidly there's
like three different layers two of which
are very distinct what I would say an
almost like modality or the tenor and
feeling of embodiment one has to do with
the feeling of the flowing of the
ability of allowing the intuition to
have free rein so one of the things that
I do is I just notice like how do I say
this like when you're actually in combat
when you're fighting somebody you don't
think too hard about it at that point
it's the time to drop the figuring out
and just allow whatever capacity you
have to make the choices you have to be
an absolute presence with what there is
in the moment so a sizeable fraction of
my time is that I'm sitting watching
everything that's going on and as soon
as I feel something arise in me I don't
try to figure out what it is I just
allow it to give to express itself
through me so for example on the past
couple of weeks I've noticed every
everyone smile something just pops up
this strikes me as being extremely clear
and needs to be expressed broadly it has
almost like a field effect it actually
feels very much like the feminine which
is to say just orienting orientation
Sensibility a couple of weeks ago I or
maybe even two days ago by the way I
apologize I've lost track of ordinary
Chronos time sent up the signal
everybody mental health be aware if
you're focused right now on the ground
if you're looking at like medical and
you're looking at-at finance or even
like just buying food for your family
anybody anywhere who has any orientation
in this direction just like pop
attention attention attention
but trying to get from me at least one
of the things that I've noticed is that
one of the characteristics that I have
been able to be a
service in the past has to do with this
ability to have a broad broad sensing
and then too quickly or notice when like
to be a scout in the sense their point
attention point of collective intention
at something and to trust that I may be
wrong I'm going to take the risk of
being wrong but hopes that also the
relationships I've built over the past
several years know how to use my signal
as I'm now committing myself to being
fully of service to what is happening
and just allowing and hoping and
trusting that the relationality and
myself and the ones around me that
there's a fluidness that can happen
there flipside is putting to work all
the work that I've now done over the
past four or five years of getting past
my own bullshit and particularly being
able to deal with other people's
bullshit and actually bringing together
practical collaborative teams in that
case by the way I'm engaging it a lot
like lots and lots and lots like 18 20
hour days all over the board some of
which are very practical like very
grizzled I'll get phone call from it
from a guy who's a formal former Special
Operations individual who was in
Afghanistan kind of person he just saw
was going on grabbed three of his
buddies jumped in a truck drove to the
Grove to the hospital and said okay how
do we help now he's covering most of
western New York and New York City with
the team of people trying to figure out
how actually solved the problem because
it turns out crisis mentality is not
typical inside civilian institutions
well okay he actually is good friends
with another person who I've spent time
with the other friend calls me and says
this is somebody you need to talk to
they think about that chain it's a chain
of trust I've built real confidence that
person B is somebody who if he tells me
to do something I don't ask what I just
do it okay I talked to person a and
immediately an interactive person a I
can enter into a mode of relationality
which is basically sort of a warband
kind of vibe say okay we're in the
middle of a crisis how do I help only
question what do you need all right
great I will do absolutely what I can
and commit no more and hand it up chain
and find other people who I'm able to
able to rapidly form those kinds of
bonds without them because I built them
through hard work over time or because
the characteristics of the environment
right now and the level
sensitivity discernment that I had in me
enables me to reach a very high trust
engagement and actually that's happening
a lot for me I'm actually having
conversations with people all over the
world or holding big chunks of stuff and
we just cut right through the bullshit
but immediately a big program is just
cutting through the bullshit jump
straight to reality
say okay I hear what you're doing it
sounds to me like you're probably
fucking up these two things if we can
help you on that I'm happy to help I
understand this is a crisis thing and
everything's breaking but this part
right here that feels really important
so let's try to get a call tomorrow a
part of ring to other people people into
it I think who will get it and let's
begin to organize around making that
happen and of course a lot of this
depends on where you are what your
particular area is right you can tell
you could just tell by the energy as you
ask that question I have a certain in my
dad's a my whole family on the male side
is military so there's a dropping into
that all right we have to organize a
particular capacity for action to make
that happen so myself I find I'm
embodying with my masculine and feminine
aspects and allowing them both to simply
do what they do without trying to think
too hard about what it is well that I
pulled that answer that question in any
useful way yeah what you're saying is
that you know don't overthinking if
we're in a time of that urgency is
immediacy is needed we just start to
directly go for something and I was
wondering if you look at it like burning
man you mentioned like look at it a top
shot and kind of loud and operate or how
that organically moves without like like
a festival the director saying I wonder
does a woman or a man or whatever saying
what we need to do we kind of
self-organized is if you see certain
trends off like there's a lot of hope
and a lot of power and energy because
you're scouting how you just mentioned
scouting like where do you see big
opportunities big big movements of
society focusing on something that kind
of like grapes in a shallow or Bowl are
very very potent right now yeah one of
the places that I'm watching
so from as a scout let's all put the
scout and rule right now
one of the places that I'm watching
right now is the moment where enough
people recognize that the poor folks who
have been put in charge of being in
charge are over their head at best
they're over their head and
unfortunately we've actually created a
niche which selects with certain
venality and banality to a pretty high
degree so at their best they're over
their head and they're really not at
their best so a whole bunch of people to
wake up to that now what happens is this
it's sad to say I got so frustrated in
2016 which was that was reality given us
a very clear sign that our political
system was not a well-functioning
machine and 2016 was reality saying hey
everybody check it out this whole kind
of vote for people in political parties
thing you've been doing for a while
ain't working but
instead of going well shit that ain't
working what could we do
almost everybody almost like after
September 11th immediately tried to RIA
news to some variation on the old system
I started pointing fingers of what was
in fact the cause when the cause was
actually it ain't working deeply but
again remember we the people are in fact
this thing to the degree to it we are
fundamentally of taking the idea of
sovereignty and moving it from the kind
of spiritual domain and moving into the
political domain at the end of the day
we have responsibility for the choices
that we make
we all are fully responsible for the
choices that we make now we have
alienated that responsibility to an
architecture of decision-making we call
politics and we have a belief that we
have powerless outside of that
architecture but that's bullshit that is
the biggest form of bullshit the reality
is is that if a few of us just a handful
of us decided you know what we're to go
ahead and tell those guys that they're
fired and we're gonna start taking
responsibility for it directly and if it
got to be a little bit bigger group it
doesn't take a whole lot of people to
just start doing things and recognizing
that that's the thing so that's gonna be
a big point and I tell you why if it
doesn't happen this time
it's gonna happen next time because
these things are gonna keep calm until
we figure it out because the system is
in fact hyper fragile I don't know if
you if you watch the news and I
recommended by the way not doing too
much of it
but what's going on in the level of
financial system is shenanigans of the
highest order you can't just take the
sign when shenanigans that went wit like
what was the guy he said like 60 in a
single press conference he's like don't
worry folks we're putting six trillion
dollars into this thing and by the way
everything's gonna be fine in two weeks
I'm pretty capable of not having radical
cognitive dissonance and that one kind
of shows up as something of that at that
order all right fair enough
and it's okay I don't need to have any
villains like I don't need to point and
pick a pick an enemy this is not Star
Wars nobody's wearing like you know
black leather uniforms most of the
people who are up there trying to do a
good job it's very hard right now
because the architectures of choice make
me put together we're
we're not designed for this kind of
system dynamic and I think about we're
running 1776 primary code in an
environment we've got 8 billion people
globally connected communicating at
Lightspeed continuously there's an
asymmetry going on there all right fair
enough time for a reboot time for us to
settle in make sure that nothing fucking
breaks in the meantime let's make sure
that things are basically taken care of
we're all sitting at home it's also
we've got food water and our families
more less ok let's let's just sit back a
bit and actually have a conversation
with other reasonable people about what
kinds of moves we might make what's the
adjacent possible so what I've been
thinking about is kind of like three
basic principles sever decoupled migrate
sever there's some things to just need
to go obvious shitty stuff that we don't
need if we just got rid of it everything
will be better tomorrow find out what it
is and let it go decouple or there's
some things that we need I'll give you
an example big agriculture unfortunately
we have put ourselves in a bit of a bind
there 66% of our productive agriculture
is back full back hold into 4% of farms
all of which are owned by large
companies well we ain't going straight
to small agriculture anytime soon that's
ok there are mechanisms where we can
decouple that and begin to create
constructs where for example the
economic system that we're in I
apologize what I'm about to say is not
easily said and it's not obvious but I
assure you that there are a very small
number of relatively practical steps
that can be put in place that will
enable this to happen we can make small
modifications to the way that we go
about doing things like money and the
way they would go about doing things
like making
making choices of who we depend on that
could be the decouples our dependence on
existing systems that over time will
naturally migrate to completely
different constructs so it's decouple
sever decouple migrate all right don't
teleport is teleportations of imaginary
Star Trek made that up it's not a real
thing but you can definitely kill stuff
that should be dead you can definitely
take step that shouldn't be stuck
together and put it in its right
relationship once you've done that then
the natural patterns of reality can take
over again and the system will begin to
naturally migrate to the to the to the
energy state that is in fact the
effective one well Jordan we're gonna be
absorbing this talk I'm going to be
sharing with other people and we're
gonna be continuing these campfires
conversations and Philly's gonna
basically wrap up what the next steps
are never gonna have root summarized in
the felt sense a song based on your talk
tonight
all right that's that's fantastic this
is how we share knowledge you know what
a felt sense and so and then after that
I'll stop the recording and the media's
hangout Thank You Jordan its I also want
to invite everybody who has a question
to put that in the chat box here to keep
that conversation and start it and get
it go and keep it going and ask Jordan
some questions and and share your story
if you want to this is one of the
campfires this is a small campfire and
we are just getting started this is the
the opening week and we hope to spread
the fire and the and the passion for for
change and innovation we will be posting
what we do the weekly programs on the
website Red Cat Club comm and if you
have any ideas of people you would like
to hear and
any ideas of what you want to see
programs the coming weeks let us know
thank you everybody and root please stay
okay it away for a moment no he's muted
unmute him John clingy Bonnie had a
lapse couldn't tell his fragility and
over-optimization would lead to his
collapse dual dynamic systems you know
we can't resist our anti fragile gypsies
there ain't no rugged individual just an
invitation to come a little closer
even if it's just digitally we'll talk
about our true desires go higher oh yeah
we'll build ourself a campfire yeah
addicted to ideology with this freedom
possibility mute the noise stop biessing
first use and me come a little closer
even if it's just digitally we'll talk
about heart's true desire going higher
yeah we'll burn ourself a camp fire
[Music]
unlearn all the dirty tricks it's hard
to be has for more than 20 days blue
it'd be like water
Oh in simplicity there is starfish
harmony so come a little closer to me
even it's just in you totally for now
Oh as the flames go higher we will
gather around the campfire
[Music]